thepaleomom.com 2019-12-16

# Privacy Policy ~ The Paleo Mom

### ThePaleoMom.com  
ThePaleoMomConsulting.com

####  **Overview**

At ThePaleoMom.com and ThePaleoMomConsulting.com (collectively, “we” or “us”), protecting your privacy and security is a top priority.  This privacy policy tells you how we use personal information collected at [www.ThePaleoMom.com](https://www.thepaleomom.com/)  and [www.ThePaleoMomConsulting.com](https://www.thepaleomomconsulting.com/) (collectively, the “Website”).  Please read this privacy policy before using the Website or submitting any personal information through the Website.   BY USING THE WEBSITE, WHETHER OR NOT YOU REGISTER, YOU ARE ACCEPTING THE PRACTICES DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND THE TERMS OF USE AGREEMENT POSTED ON THE WEBSITE.  This Privacy Policy may be changed, but any changes will be posted and changes will only apply to activities and information on a going forward, not retroactive basis. You are encouraged to review the privacy policy whenever you visit the Website to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.

 **Note:** the privacy practices set forth in this privacy policy are for the Website only. If you link to other websites, including those of Providers (as defined in the Terms of Use), please review the privacy policies posted at those sites.

####  _ **Traffic Data**_

We reserve the right to gather certain generic information with respect to use of the Website, such as the number of unique visitors, the frequency with which they visit, and the areas on the Website that they favor. These statistics are very much like television ratings that tell the networks how many people tuned in to a program. We only use this type of data in aggregate, that is we look at the data on a collective basis, in summary form, rather than on an individual basis. This data helps us determine the extent to which our members use certain parts of the Website, which, in turn, enables us to make it as appealing as possible. We may also provide statistical “ratings” about how our members collectively use the Website to Providers, advertisers, sponsors, affiliates, and other companies with which we do business (“Partners”). We do this so they, too, can understand how often people use their areas of the Website in order for them to provide you witcooh the best possible experience. These statistical ratings do not contain any personally identifiable information about you or any of our members.

We may collect and analyze traffic on the Website by keeping track of the IP addresses of our visitors. IP addresses are unique numeric identifiers that are assigned to each computer browser accessing the Internet. An IP address, by itself, cannot identify you personally. However, when combined with other information provided by your Internet Service Provider (ISP), your IP address can be used to identify the computer originating a message.

We may store all Traffic Data and review postings indefinitely, even after “deletion,” and may archive such information elsewhere. We may store all information until you request that we modify or delete it, in which case we may still retain certain information for the reasons described in this Privacy Policy or in the Terms of Use.

####  _ **Cookies, Web Beacons and Analytics**_ __

We may use “cookies” on the Website. Cookies are pieces of information or data sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive for record-keeping purposes, and to improve the Website experience. We use cookies to make your visit to the Website easier. For example, cookies allow us to recognize you when you re-enter the Website so that you will not have to sign-in each time you visit. Cookies also allow us to count the number of unique and return visitors who use the Website. Cookies do not allow our site to gain access to other information on your computer Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can reset your browser to notify you when you’ve received a cookie or, alternatively, to refuse to accept cookies. It is important to note that you may not be able to use certain features on the Website if you choose not to accept cookies. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our members to enhance their experience on the Website.

You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject third-party cookies. By visiting this Website and scrolling our web pages, we assume you accept these third-party cookies. We provide you with a way to reject acceptance on your initial visit to our site. You may also reject third-party cookies at any time by clicking the button below.

You have accepted our cookie policy. [cookies_revoke]

We may use tiny graphic image files imbedded in a web page or email (“Web Beacons”) to collect anonymous, non-personal information about your use of the Website and the sites of selected sponsors, affiliates and advertisers, and your use of emails, special promotions or newsletters we send to you. The information collected by Web Beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using the Website and selected sponsors, affiliates and advertisers sites, or opening our emails, and for what purposes.

We may use third party website analytics services in connection with the Website, for example, to record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity, as well as any text that you type into the Website.  These analytical tools do not collect personal information that you do not voluntarily enter into the Website.  These services do not track your browsing habits across websites which do not use their services. We use the information collected from these services to find usability problems to make the Website easier to use.  The recordings will never identify you or your account; they only record anonymous user information.

We may share your anonymized information with third parties to enable them to run statistical research on individual or aggregate health, fitness or nutrition trends.

####  _ **Third Party Advertiser Cookies**_ __

We may use third-party advertising companies to provide and service our advertisements on the Internet. These third-party advertising companies may employ cookie or other technology to measure and improve the effectiveness of advertisements.  To do so, these companies may use anonymous information about your visits to the Website and other websites. This information may include: date/time of banner ad shown, the banner ad that was shown, their cookie, the IP address. This information can also be used for online preference marketing purposes. ThePaleoMom.com does not use or have access to this information.

If you want to prevent a third-party advertiser from setting and/or reading cookies on your computer, currently you may either visit each ad network’s Website individually and opt out or visit the Website of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) to opt-out of all network-advertising cookies. [Click here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp) for the NAI gateway opt-out site.  This website will also allow you to review the third-party advertising companies’ privacy policies.

The Website may contain links to third party websites to which we have no affiliation. We do not share your personal information with those websites and are not responsible for their privacy practices. Some websites may have the look and feel of our Website. Please be aware that you may be on a different website and that this Privacy Policy only covers our Website. A link to a website not subject to this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use does not constitute or imply endorsement by us. Additionally, we cannot guarantee the quality or accuracy of information presented on other parties websites. Should you decide to visit one of these third party websites, we suggest that you read its privacy policy.

####  **Collection and Distribution of Information** **  
**

We may collect personally identifiable information, including, but not limited to, names, postal addresses, email addresses, and information necessary to provide Services (as defined in the Terms of Use posted elsewhere on the Website), when voluntarily submitted by our visitors and users.

If you have provided us your consent, we will use the information we have collected about you:

  * To send personalized, targeted information that we think our members will find relevant, either from the Website directly or from Providers, business partners or affiliates;
  * To include targeted advertising within such messages;
  * To send promotions or coupons based upon the members interests;
  * To contact the user for feedback and surveys; and
  * To send the user other information about ThePaleoMom.com.

You may choose not to provide us with any personal information.  In such an event, you can still access the Website and use some of the Services; however you may not be able to access and use certain key features of the Website that require registration.

If you do not wish to receive such communications, you can send an e-mail to policy@thePaleomom.com and you will be removed from the list.   In addition, e-mails and newsletters from the Website will allow you to opt out of future mailings.

####  **Distribution of Information**

Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we will keep your personal information private and will not share it with third parties.  However, we may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may share your non- anonymized information as described in the Terms of Use, as well as:

  * To comply with legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena or court order;
  * To protect the company’s rights and property;
  * To investigate reports of members sending material using a false e-mail address or members sending harassing, threatening, or abusive messages;
  * To protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Website and/or the Services;
  * To enforce the Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy; or
  * During emergencies, such as when we believe someone’s physical safety is at risk.

The information is not provided to these companies for marketing purposes.

####  **Commitment to Data Security**

Your personally identifiable information will be kept secure.  We will use commercially reasonable efforts to permit only authorized employees, agents and contractors (who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential) to have access to your information, and to help safeguard personal information from unauthorized access, alteration or disclosure.

Although we make good faith efforts to store personal information in a secure operating environment that is not open to the public, you should understand that there is no such thing as complete security, and we do not guarantee that there will be no unintended disclosures of your information.  If we become aware that your information has been disclosed in a manner not in accordance with this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you of the nature and extent of the disclosure (to the extent we know that information) as soon as reasonably possible and as permitted by law.

Providers (as defined in the Terms of Use), their employees, and their agents should be particularly aware of their obligations of confidentiality, including any obligations which may arise under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (“HIPAA”), both in communicating with us and in responding to a review of their services as may be posted on the Website.  We do not have, and will not accept, any obligations of confidentiality with respect to any communications other than those expressly stated in this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use.

####  _ **Mandatory Communications**_ __

ThePaleoMom.com reserves the right to communicate with you from time to time about important administrative, policy or other matters, which will affect your use of the Website, including without limitation any alleged violations of our Terms of Use; these communications are mandatory.

 **Sale of Assets**

In the event that ThePaleoMom.com and/or its units or subsidiaries are ever sold, acquired, merged, liquidated, reorganized, or otherwise transferred, we reserve the right to transfer our user databases together with any personally identifiable information contained therein, to the party acquiring ThePaleoMom.com’s assets. In the event we do so, we will place a notice of the sale on the homepage of the Website, with links to information as to how you can change your privacy preferences.

####  ** **

####  **Use Common Sense in All Your Online Activities**

Any information that you may reveal in a review posting or other online discussion or forum is intentionally open to the public and is not in private. You should think carefully before disclosing any personally identifiable information in any public forum.

Even the best policy can’t protect your online privacy and security in all circumstances. Unscrupulous advertisers, hackers, and scam artists are constantly searching the Internet looking for new targets. Your best protection is to understand the limits to privacy on the Internet and use common sense in all of your on-line activities.

Be aware that e-mail is an inherently unsecure form of communication. Remember that third-parties are sometimes able to illegally intercept your unencrypted messages.

Anytime you visit a blog or post a message to an on-line bulletin board, your e-mail address can be accessed by advertisers looking to compile lists for unsolicited commercial e-mail (“ spam”). Be sure that you only disclose your e-mail address in circumstances in which it is safe to do so.

Beware of scams in which persons unknown to you request your personal information. Make sure you verify the identity of anyone asking for personal information. Always monitor your children’s on-line activities and educate them as to the rules for safe Internet use.

You must promptly notify us if your contact data is lost, stolen, or used without permission. In such an event, we will remove that contact data from your account and update our records accordingly.

####  **Children’s privacy**

Although the Website is available to general audiences, the website is not directed to children.  As per the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (15 U.S.C. 6501, _et seq._ ), we do not knowingly collect or maintain personal information from persons under the age of 13.

####  **Privacy Contact Information**

If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about our privacy policy you may contact us using the information below:

By e-mail: policy@thePaleomom.com

We reserve the right to make changes to this policy. Any changes to this policy will be posted.
